Finding Aid for the Nan Britton Papers, 1902-1966
UCLA Library, Department of Special Collections
Nan Britton Papers,
1902-1966
467
Britton, Nan, 1896-
13 boxes (6.5 linear ft.) 1 oversize box
University of California, Los Angeles. Library. Department of Special Collections. Los Angeles, California 90095-1575
Administrative Information
Restrictions on Access
PARTIALLY PROCESSED COLLECTION UNAVAILABLE FOR USE: Inquiries regarding these materials should be directed, in writing, to the Manuscripts Librarian, UCLA Department of Special Collections.
COLLECTION STORED OFF-SITE AT SRLF: Advance notice required for access.
Additional Physical Form Available
A copy of the original version of this online finding aid is available at the UCLA Department of Special Collections for in-house consultation and may be obtained for a fee. Please contact:
Public Services Division
UCLA Library, Department of Special Collections
Room A1713, Charles E. Young Research Library
Box 951575
Los Angeles, CA 90095-1575
Telephone: 310/825-4988 (10:00 a.m. - 4:45 p.m., Pacific Time)
Email: spec-coll@library.ucla.edu
Scope and Content
Collection consists of correspondence, manuscripts, clippings, photographs, and memorabilia.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Britton, Nan, b. 1896--Archives.; Harding, Warren G. (Warren Gamaliel), 1865-1923.; Women authors, American--Archival resources.; Manuscripts for publication.
Container List
- Books
  - Murphy, James W. Last Speeches of President Warren G. Harding, 1923. (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Johnson, Willis Fletcher. The Life of Warren G. Harding, 1923. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Asher, Carl. He Was Just Folks, 1923. (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - In Memoriam - Warren G. Harding, 1924. (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Blythe, Samuel G. A Calm Review of a Calm Man, 1923. (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Means, Gaston. The Strange Death of President Harding, 1930. (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Jenks, Anton Shrewsbury. A Dead President Makes Answer to The President's Daughter, 1928. (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - DeBarthe, Joseph. The Answer, 1928. (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Sytton, Dan. The Vice President's Son, 1928. (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Smith, Ina R.T. Dear Mr. President, 1949. (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Our Common Country, speeches of Warren G. Harding 1921. (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - The Mirrors of Washington, 1921. (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Allen, Frederic Lewis. Only Yesterday, 1931. (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Britton, Nan. The President's Daughter, 1930., With First Edition attached to flyleaf. (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Britton, Nan. Honesty or Politics, 1932., With photocopy of dustjacket. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Britton, Nan. Mes Amours Avec Le President Harding, 1931. (Box 17, Folder 6)
- Correspondence
  - Charles E. Kelley (Nan Britton's New York attorney), 1928., Folders 1 and 2 of 5. (Box 8, Folder 15-16)
  - Charles E. Kelley (Nan Britton's New York attorney) 1930-1931., Folder 4 of 5. (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Charles E. Kelley (Nan Britton's New York attorney), 1928-1930., Folder 3 of 5. (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Charles E. Kelley (Nan Britton's New York attorney), 1932-1936., Folder 5 of 5. (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Nathan Loeser (one of Nan Britton's attorneys in Cleveland), 1928., Folder 1 of 5. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Nathan Loeser (one of Nan Britton's attorneys in Cleveland), 1928-1929., Folder 2 of 5. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Nathan Loeser (one of Nan Britton's attorneys in Cleveland), 1929-1930., Folder 3 of 5. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Nathan Loeser (one of Nan Britton's attorneys in Cleveland), 1930., Folder 4 of 5. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Nathan Loeser (one of Nan Britton's attorneys in Cleveland), 1930-1931., Folder 5 of 5. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - William F. Marsteller and Seavey Moor, 1927., Folder 1 of 9. Labelled The situation in Cleveland. (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - William F. Marsteller and Seavey Moor, 1931., Folder 2 of 9. Samples of letters and orders received concerning the DeBarthe book, and replies thereto. (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - William F. Marsteller and Seavey Moor, 1928-1930., Folder 3 of 9. re Mr. Fryefield. (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - William F. Marsteller and Seavey Moor, 1929-1930., Folder 4 of 9. (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - William F. Marsteller and Seavey Moor, 1931., Folder 5 of 9. (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - William F. Marsteller and Seavey Moor, 1931., Folders 6 through 8 of 9. (Box 9, Folder 11-12, Box 10, Folder 1)
  - William F. Marsteller and Seavey Moor, 1932., Folder 9 of 9. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - William F. Marsteller and Mrs. Britton (Nan's mother) re McDowell sisters, 1928-1931. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Frank Vincent and George Landy, 1930., re proposed film of The President's Daughter. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Elizabeth Ann Guild, Incorporated - miscellaneous, 1927-1933., Folder 1 of 2. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Elizabeth Ann Guild, Incorporated - miscellaneous, 1927-1933., Folder 2 of 2. Includes financial reports for 1927. (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Elizabeth Ann Guild, Incorporated - sheets from minute book and other papers, 1927-1928., Folder 1 of 4. (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Elizabeth Ann Guild, Incorporated - sheets from minute book and other papers, 1928-1932., Folder 2 of 4. (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Elizabeth Ann Guild, Incorporated - sheets from minute book and other papers, 1927-1932., Folder 3 of 4. (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Elizabeth Ann Guild, Incorporated - sheets from minute book and other papers, 1929-1931., Folder 4 of 4. Includes material re the Golden Rule Foundation. (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Elizabeth Ann Guild, Incorporated - general - Toussaint Dubois, 1927-1928., Folder 1 of 7. (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Elizabeth Ann Guild, Incorporated - general - Gordon Lathrop, 1927-1928., Folder 2 of 7. (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Elizabeth Ann Guild, Incorporated - general - Harold West and Rev. and Mrs. Cyril Wyche, 1928-1929., Folder 3 of 7. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Elizabeth Ann Guild, Incorporated - general - John Haynes Holmes, 1927-1928., Folder 4 of 7. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Elizabeth Ann Guild, Incorporated - general, 1927-1932., Folder 5 of 7. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Elizabeth Ann Guild, Incorporated - general, 1928., Folder 6 of 7. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Elizabeth Ann Guild, Incorporated--general, 1927-1928., Folder 7 of 7. With mockup of brochure for Elizabeth Ann League. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Elizabeth Ann Guild, Incorporated--memberships, 1927-1928., Folder 1 of 3. (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Elizabeth Ann Guild, Incorporated--memberships, 1928-1929., Folder 2 of 3. (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Elizabeth Ann Guild, Incorporated--memberships, 1928-1932., Folder 3 of 3. (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Elizabeth Ann Guild, Incorporated--requests for illegitimacy statistics, 1927-1928., 3 folders. (Box 11, Folder 9-10, Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Elizabeth Ann Guild, Incorporated--letters from friends, 1927-1929., Folders 1 and 2 of 4. (Box 12, Folder 2-3)
  - Elizabeth Ann Guild, Incorporated--letters from friends, 1928-1931., Folder 3 of 4. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Elizabeth Ann Guild, Incorporated--letters from friends, 1931., Folder 4 of 4. (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Letters from readers of The President's Daughter answered by Nan Britton, her sister or current secretary, 1927-1931., Folder 1 of 5. (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Letters from readers of The President's Daughter answered by Nan Britton, her sister or current secretary, 1928-1931., Folders 2, 4 and 5 of 5. (Box 13, Folder 1, 3-5)
  - Letters from readers of The President's Daughter answered by Nan Britton, her sister or current secretary, 1926-1931. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Letters from readers of The President's Daughter regarding the League's work, 1928-1931., 6 folders. (Box 13, Folder 5-8, Box 14, Folder 1-2)
  - Richard Wightman, 1926-1928., Folder 1 of 3. See Honesty or Politics, ch. 6, 7, 9, 11, 15. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Richard Wightman, 1926-1928., Folder 2 and 3 of 3. (Box 14, Folder 4-5)
  - Nicholas Paul Perry, C. Michael Morssen, Matrujillo, Mr. Winston, Paramount Pictures and others, 1931-1933, 1947, 1951. (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Louis Postif, Clifton Fadiman, Curtis Brown, Limited, A. C. Boni, Incorporated and others, 1930-1935. (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Requests for interviews with Nan Britton following the publicity re the Phillips letters. 1964-1965. (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Randolph C. Downes, University of Toledo, 1960-1965. (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Dean Albertson, Brooklyn College, 1936-1964. (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - W.F. Shelton, Francis Russell, Warren Boroson (Fact Magazine), 1963-1964. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Edwin K. Gross, 1964-1965. (Box 15, Folder 2)
- Documentary Files
  - Letter from Warren G. Harding to Nan Britton, [1917] May 9., Written on U.S. Senate stationery (with envelope). 3pp. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letter from Warren G. Harding to Nan Britton, May 15, 1917., Written on Senate Chamber stationery, 4pp. (2 leaves). (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Letter from Warren G. Harding to Nan Britton, August 11, 1917., Written on U.S. Senate stationery, 1 leaf. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Letter from Warren G. Harding to Nan Britton, May 25, 1918., Written on U.S. Senate, Committee on Commerce stationery, 2pp. with franked envelope. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Letter from Warren G. Harding to Nan Britton, December 5, 1918., Written on U.S. Senate, Committee on Commerce stationery, 1-1/2 pages, no envelope. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Letter from Warren G. Harding to Dr. Frank T. Spaulding, Superintendent of Public Schools, Cleveland, Ohio, May 25, 1918., Regarding my mother's changing her position as teacher. Letter of May 25, 1918 (above) sent to me same date. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Carbon copy of letter from Nan Britton to Warren G. Harding, May 7, 1917., Sent to him at Washington, D.C., to which he replied under date of May 9. Attached ia copy of carbon re-typed for clarity. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Carbon copy of letter from Nan Britton to Warren G. Harding, May 11, 1917., ... in reply to his letter of me of May 9; also re-typed for clarity. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Letter to Nan Britton from her mother November 1, 1926., ... regarding the latter's misplacement of a letter written by Senator Harding to Mark Thompson, who was also with the Cleveland Public Schools as President of the Board of Education.... With envelope. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Letter from Abigail V. Harding to S.A. Willits and Miss Nan Britton, February 2, 1920. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Letter from Abigail V. Harding to Elizabeth and Nan Britton, June 1, 1920 (probably). (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Letter from Abigail V. Harding to Nan Britton, July 24, 1920. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Letter from Abigail V. Harding to Nan Britton October 6, 1920., With envelope. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Letter from Abigail V. Harding to Nan Britton, October 15, 1921., With envelope. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Letter from Abigail V. Harding to Nan Britton, January 30, 1922., Dated per envelope. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Letter from Abigail V. Harding to Nan Britton, July 1, 1922. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Letter from Abigail V. Harding to Nan Britton, July 26, 1922. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Letter from Abigail V. Harding to Elizabeth and Nan Britton, October 7, 1922. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Letter from Abigail V. Harding to Nan Britton, May 14, 1923., Dated per envelope. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Letter from Abigail V. Harding to Mrs. Magnus Ericksen (Nan Britton), February 2, 1924. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Letter from Abigail V. Harding to Mrs. Magnus Ericksen (Nan Britton), May 27, 1924., Dated per envelope. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Letter from Abigail V. Harding to Mrs. Magnus Ericksen (Nan Britton) December 24, 1924., ... written Christmas Eve, 1924, after her marriage to Ralph T. Lewis, from the Princess Hotel in Bermuda where they were honeymooning - I did not keep the envelope. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Letter from Ralph T. Lewis to Mrs. Magnus Ericksen (Nan Britton), December 26, 1924. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Letter from Abigail V. Harding to Nan Britton, n.d. (Saturday the 7th). (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Abigail V. Harding to Nan Britton Ericksen, May 18, 1925., Dated per envelope. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Letter from Abigail V. Harding to Nan Britton Ericksen, May 25, 1925., Dated per envelope. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Letter from Abigail V. Harding to Nan Britton Ericksen, September 8, 1925., Dated per envelope. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Abigail V. Harding (carbon copy), September 23, 1925. (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Abigail V. Harding (carbon copy), October 5, 1925. (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Letter Nan Britton to Mrs. Carolyn H. Votaw (carbon copy), September 23, 1925. (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Letter from Mrs. Carolyn H. Votaw to Mrs. Nan B. Ericksen, September 25, 1925., With envelope. (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Telegram from Mrs. A.A. Stuart (assumed name of Abigail v. Harding) to Nan B. Ericksen, October 7, 1925. (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Abigail V. Harding (carbon copy) October 8, 1925. (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Letter from Abigail V. Harding to Nan B. Ericksen, October 13 (?), 1925., Mr. Wightman wrote on the envelope 'main admissions - important and I wrote 'Talks of effect my letter had on Mr. Mrs. Votaw.' (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Abigail V. Harding (carbon copy), October 16, 1925. (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Abigail V. Harding (carbon copy), November 12, 1925., Mr. Votaw had returned to me my 'Action to Annual a Marriage' which I had sent him to view, but he sent it back without any comment or note. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Mr. And Mrs. Votaw (carbon copy) with return receipt attached, October 18, 1925. (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Abigail V. Harding, October 19, 1925. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Abigail V. Harding (carbon copy), October 22, 1925. (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Letter from Abigail V. Harding to Nan B. Ericksen, October 20, 1925., Dated per envelope. (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Abigail V. Harding (carbon copy), November 2, 1925. (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Letter from Abigail V. Harding to Nan B. Ericksen, November 5, 1925., Dated per envelope. (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Letter from Abigail V. Harding to Nan B. Ericksen, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Letter to Abigail V. Harding from Nan Britton (carbon copy) with bills for purchases for Elizabeth Ann attached, November 1, 1925. (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Letter from Abigail V. Harding to Nan B. Ericksen, December 9, 1925., Dated per envelope. (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Abigail V. Harding (carbon copy), December 11, 1925. (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Heber Herbert Votaw (carbon copy), January 27, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Letter from H.H. Votaw to Nan Britton, January 29, 1926., With envelope. (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Letter to H.H. Votaw from Nan Britton (carbon copy), January 28, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to H.H. Votaw (carbon copy) with registration receipt, January 30, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Letter from Abigail V.Harding (Lewis) to Nan B. Ericksen, February 10, 1926., Dated per envelope. (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Telegram from Abigail V. Harding to Nan B. Ericksen, February 5, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Telegram from Abigail V. Harding to Nan B. Britton, February 6, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Abigail V. Harding (carbon copy), February 1926., Saturday, 10:00 p.m. (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Mr. And Mrs. Votaw (carbon copy), February 1926., Saturday evening. (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Text of telegram from Nan Britton to Abigail V. Harding (carbon copy), February 5, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Abigail V. Harding (carbon copy) with registration receipt attached, February 5, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Abigail V. Harding (carbon copy), February 12, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Letter from Abigail V. Harding to Nan Britton, February 24, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Abigail V. Harding (carbon copy), March 7, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Abigail V. Harding (carbon copy), March 14, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Letter from Abigail V. Harding to Nan B. Ericksen, March 20, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Abigail V. Harding, March 24, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Letter from Abigail V. Harding to Nan B. Ericksen, March 25, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Abigail V. Harding (carbon copy), April 4, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Dr. Harding, brother of Warren Harding (carbon copy), April 4, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Abigail V. Harding (carbon copy), April 30, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Facsimile of bank draft from Abigail V. Harding to Nan Britton for $40.00, July 2, 1926., Marion County Bank Company, no.A16827. With envelope. (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Abigail V. Harding (carbon copy), July 7, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Letter from Abigail v. Harding enclosing money orde, with facsimile of the money order, June 4, 1926., Written from Troy, Ohio, but postmarked Hillsboro. (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Abigail V. Harding (carbon copy) June 17, 1926., With envelope. (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Letter from Abigail V. Harding to Nan Britton, July 16, 1926., With envelope. (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Abigail V. Harding (carbon copy), July 22, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Letter from Abigail V. Harding to Nan Britton, August 7, 1926., Dated per envelope. With Nan Britton's note, This was the last letter received from Miss H. (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Christmas card from Abigail V. Harding to Nan Britton, unsigned, December 21, 1926., With envelope. Nan Britton's note: containing a cashier's check for $25.00. (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Letter from Abigail V. Harding to Nan Britton's sister, Elizabeth, 1924(?). (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Calling card for Abigail Victoria Harding, 1911., Nan Britton's note: ... accompanied a little gift to me back in my high school days ... (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Calling card for Heber Herbert Votaw, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Calling card for Harry W. Perrin, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Jim Sloan (carbon copy) with return receipt, February 5, 1926., Return receipt dated February 5, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Text of telegram from Nan Britton to Jim Sloan (carbon copy), February 1926. (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Letter from Jim Sloan to Nan Britton, March 19, 1926., With envelope. (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Jim Sloan (carbon copy), March 20, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Jim Sloan (carbon copy), March 24, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Note from Jim Sloan to Nan Britton, May 18, 1926., With envelope. (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Harding Memorial Association (carbon copy), May 19, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Jim Sloan (carbon copy), May 20, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Jim Sloan (carbon copy), May 25, 1926., With program from laying of the cornerstone for the Harding Memorial. (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - Letter from Jim Sloan to Nan Britton, November 8, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - Letter from Jim Sloan to Nan Britton, January 18, 1927., Sent to Nan Britton in care of a friend. (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - Letter from Pris to Nan Britton, March 16, 1927., With envelope. (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Gen. Charles E. Dawes (carbon copy), May 15, 1926., Nan Britton's note: See The President's Daughter, episode no.166, p.379 re this. (Box 1, Folder 92)
  - Photograph of Warren G. Harding inscribed To Miss Nan Britton ... Sincerely, Warren G. Harding. n.d. (Box 1, Folder 93)
  - Photograph of Miss Abigail Victoria Harding (later Mrs. Ralph T. Lewis) inscribed: Most sincerely yours, Abigail Victoria Harding. n.d. (Box 1, Folder 94)
  - Photograph of Carolyn Harding (Mrs. Heber Herbert Votaw, inscribed: Yours truly, Carolyn Votaw. n.d. (Box 1, Folder 95)
  - Photograph of Dr. George Tryon Harding, father fo Warren G. Harding, Victoria and Carolyn Harding, inscribed: Yours truly, G.T. Harding. n.d. (Box 1, Folder 96)
  - Photograph of Lila Wesener, inscribed: To Miss Nan Britton -- / With and all good wishes from / her admiring friend, ' Lila Wesener. n.d., Nan Britton's note The latter inscription was cut from the photograph because I wanted to frame the latter 'close-up' but I kept the inscription. Lila Wesener was a cousin of the Harding sisters and brothers. (Box 1, Folder 97)
  - Wallet of Warren G. Harding, n.d., Nan Britton's note: ... (his name imprinted in gold), given to me by Carrie Votaw when I was a guest in their home in Tacoma Park, Washington, D.C. (see p.308, The President's Daughter). (Box 1, Folder 98)
  - Notarized statement of Mrs. Mary Lee Britton (Nan Britton's mother) regarding a visit of Elizabeth Britton Willits (Nan Brittons sister) to Mr. Harding at Marion, Ohio, after the election, August 4, 1928., 15pp. Holograph. (Box 1, Folder 99)
  - Statement from Nan Britton's sister, Elizabeth Britton Willits, regarding her knowledge of Nan Britton's receipt of letters from Mr. Harding, January 4, 1960., Notarized. (Box 1, Folder 100)
  - Letter from Mrs. Jack (Mary) Pusey regarding her suspicions of Mr. Harding's paternity and Nan Britton's reply (carbon copy), December 31, 1931 and January 2, 1932., Dated per envelope. Mrs. Pusey called Mrs. P.J. Johnson in The President's Daughter. Nan Britton's note: I resided in the home (apartment) of the Puseys for two years during which time I was seeing Mr. Harding. (Box 1, Folder 101)
  - Snapshot of Warren G. Harding which Nan Britton loved and carried for years. n.d., Nan Britton's additional note: This one is in The President's Daughter, opposite p.60. (Snapshot sent to me by Warren G. Harding). (Box 1, Folder 102)
  - Another Snapshot of Warren G. Harding which Nan Britton loved and carried almost as long as the one above. n.d., Nan Britton's note: (This one acquired I don't recall how. It appears to have been taken at the White House). (Box 1, Folder 103)
  - Snapshot of Nan Britton, Harding booster in the pre-election days of 1920. 1920., Taken on Labor Day. (Box 1, Folder 104)
  - Photograph of Mr. Harding taken at Edmonston Studio, Washington, D.C, n.d., Nan Britton's note: This was the first photograph Mr. Harding sent me - when I lived at 412 E. 58th St., New York City, with my father's college classmate's family (Mr. Mrs. Grove D. Curtis and daughter Anna), in the spring of 1917. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper picture of Abigail and Carolyn, 1920. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Photograph of Warren G. Harding by Pach, 1920., Nan Britton's note: ... displayed in the Pach Fifth Avenue window in August of 1923. Returning from France on learning of Mr. Harding's death, I chanced to see it and bought this copy. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Letter from the Ithaca Conservatory of Music to Scott Willits (Nan Britton's brother-in-law), part of letter from Elizabeth Willits and Nan Britton's note re this letter, December 18, 1920., Nan Britton's note: I took this letter with me when I met Mr. Harding at the Statler Hotel in Cleveland ..., see p.143 - Ep. 58, The President's Daughter. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Letter from Governor James M. Cox of Ohio to Nan Britton, June 28, 1918., Nan Brittons note: ... offering to assist my brother find a suitable position. My brother never used the letter ... see p.161, episode 64 in The President's Daughter. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Glossy print of a photograph of President Harding and full-length snapshot of Elizabeth Ann Harding - The Likeness. n.d., See p.197, The President's Daughter. (Box 2, Folder 6)